<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>web on Hugo O. Rivera</title><link>/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in web on Hugo O. Rivera</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 18:25:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Animated Periodic Table D3</title><link>/projects/animated-periodic-table-d3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 18:25:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/animated-periodic-table-d3/</guid><description>A periodic table created in CoffeeScript and D3 with animated transitions.</description></item><item><title>HelloWorlds</title><link>/projects/helloworlds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 06:56:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/helloworlds/</guid><description>What is programming? Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find lots of introductory projects for many of different applications written in a variety of notable programming languages.</description></item><item><title>Intro to programming using Python at Equipo Academy’s College Simulation Day</title><link>/tutorials/intro_to_cs.equipo.1127/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 22:53:34 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/intro_to_cs.equipo.1127/</guid><description>A programming tutorial.</description></item><item><title>Programmer-for-hire</title><link>/swe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/swe/</guid><description>I may be available for software engineering contracting work.
With my full stack skillset, I can create (or update) a website, webapp, or Android app from start to finish.
Programming Languages I know the following languages:
Python including Tensorflow and other machine learning and data science tools. JavaScript including ES6, NodeJS, and other web development tools C C++, including Qt and the language QML Java Haskell Elm Lisp Rust I have experience with the Linux operating system.</description></item><item><title>Tutoring</title><link>/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutoring/</guid><description>I am your math, language, and programming tutor Qualifications: I worked as a tutor at the Computer Science department of the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology for two years. I have a degree in mathematics and a degree in computer science from the same school, where I graduated with a 3.5 GPA in 4.5 years. I tutored middle-school as part of the Growing Up Thinking Scientifically (GUTS) program and high-school students in the Supercomputing Challenge.</description></item><item><title>does-it-live</title><link>/projects/does-it-live/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 23:22:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/does-it-live/</guid><description>Website uptime checker</description></item><item><title>nodejs-api-starter</title><link>/projects/nodejs-api-starter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 06:08:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/nodejs-api-starter/</guid><description>Boilerplate and tooling for authoring data API backends with Node.js and GraphQL. A personal fork.</description></item></channel></rss>