<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ocaml on Hugo O. Rivera's website</title><link>https://roguh.com/tags/ocaml/</link><description>Recent content in ocaml on Hugo O. Rivera's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roguh.com/tags/ocaml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Programmer-for-hire</title><link>https://roguh.com/swe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/swe/</guid><description>I may be available for software engineering contracting work.
With my full stack skillset, I can create (or update) a website, webapp, or Android app from start to finish.
Programming Languages I know the following languages:
Python including Tensorflow and other machine learning and data science tools. JavaScript including ES6, NodeJS, and other web development tools C C++, including Qt and the language QML Java Haskell Elm Lisp Rust I have experience with the Linux operating system.</description></item><item><title>Tutoring</title><link>https://roguh.com/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/tutoring/</guid><description>I am your math, language, and programming tutor Qualifications: I worked as a tutor at the Computer Science department of the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology for two years. I have a degree in mathematics and a degree in computer science from the same school, where I graduated with a 3.5 GPA in 4.5 years. I tutored middle-school as part of the Growing Up Thinking Scientifically (GUTS) program and high-school students in the Supercomputing Challenge.</description></item><item><title>Parser and Interpreter in OCaml</title><link>https://roguh.com/projects/hrclox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 20:21:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/projects/hrclox/</guid><description>Lox interpreter written in OCaml by Hugo O. Rivera Calzadillas. See github.com/roguh/hrclox.
Based off https://craftinginterpreters.com.
Boilerplate code for writing parsers in OCaml using Menhir + sedlex See github.com/roguh/ocaml-parsing
(Unfinished, but the parser is fairly complete)</description></item></channel></rss>