<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo O. Rivera's website</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Hugo O. Rivera's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Async Python Tricks</title><link>/tutorials/python_asyncio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/python_asyncio/</guid><description>Code Starting an Async Program In Python 3.7 and above, you can use asyncio.run to easily start your async program:
async def async_main(): await asyncio.sleep(1) print(&amp;quot;Async&amp;quot;) def main(): asyncio.run(async_main(), debug=True) if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;: main() Alternatives To run an async program in other ways, you need to use the loop directly.
loop = asyncio.get_running_loop() loop.run_until_complete if you have one function you need to run loop.run_forever if you never want to close the async loop Running blocking synchronous functions after Python 3.</description></item><item><title>Async Python: Debug Mode and Warnings</title><link>/tutorials/python_asyncio_warnings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/python_asyncio_warnings/</guid><description>Enable Debug Mode Warnings about blocking async code In debug mode, you will get warnings about async code that blocks for too long as well as other warnings.
Example code:
import asyncio import time async def blocks(): print(&amp;quot;START&amp;quot;) # Synchronous blocking code time.sleep(0.35) await asyncio.sleep(0.5) # Synchronous blocking code time.sleep(0.15) await asyncio.sleep(0.1) print(&amp;quot;DONE&amp;quot;) asyncio.run(blocks(), debug=True) Output:
START Executing &amp;lt;Task pending name='Task-804' coro=&amp;lt;blocks() running at &amp;lt;ipython-input-7-1388d45e4cc5&amp;gt;:4&amp;gt; wait_for=&amp;lt;Future pending cb=[&amp;lt;TaskWakeupMethWrapper object at 0x7f71d70e7910&amp;gt;()] created at /usr/lib/python3.</description></item><item><title>Link to Presentation for Equipo College Simulation Day</title><link>/e/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 09:00:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/e/</guid><description>Go here: roguh.com/intro.equipo.2021.11</description></item><item><title>Link to Presentation for Equipo College Simulation Day</title><link>/equipo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 09:00:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/equipo/</guid><description>Go here: roguh.com/intro.equipo.2021.11</description></item><item><title>Intro to programming using Python at Equipo Academy’s College Simulation Day</title><link>/tutorials/intro_to_cs.equipo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 22:53:34 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/intro_to_cs.equipo/</guid><description>A programming tutorial given over the years.</description></item><item><title>Configuration files for Linux/MacOS</title><link>/projects/confs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 20:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/confs/</guid><description>My dotfiles and a script to quickly backup and restore them.</description></item><item><title>Shellscripts: parallely, gp, and makeanywhere</title><link>/projects/shellscripts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 19:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/shellscripts/</guid><description>Several useful shellscripts</description></item><item><title>pipemath</title><link>/projects/pipemath/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:29:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/pipemath/</guid><description>Run math functions on number from stdin</description></item><item><title>rust-api</title><link>/projects/rust_api/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 12:29:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/rust_api/</guid><description>A proof of concept for a full featured Rust HTTP API</description></item><item><title>the_long_count</title><link>/projects/the_long_count/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/the_long_count/</guid><description>Some functions for computing using the Long Count, a Mayan numeric system for dates.</description></item><item><title>hrpypy</title><link>/projects/hrpypy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 09:29:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/hrpypy/</guid><description>Mini Python interpreter in Python by Hugo O. Rivera Calzadillas</description></item><item><title>rust-ls</title><link>/projects/rust-ls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 12:29:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/rust-ls/</guid><description>List all files in a directory</description></item><item><title>i3empty</title><link>/projects/i3empty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 02:28:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/i3empty/</guid><description>Quickly switch to a new numbered workspace. Utility for the i3 window manager.</description></item><item><title>Interview Prep</title><link>/posts/interview-prep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 15:50:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/interview-prep/</guid><description>Advice I found useful.</description></item><item><title>New Science</title><link>/news/industry/new-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:05:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/industry/new-science/</guid><description>Complexity Accept chaos.
Machine Learning Applied mathematics with the power of modern supercomputers. Advanced optimization, linear algebra, calculus.
Effectiveness of techniques revolutionized by deep learning.
Climate Change Consequences of pollution known for about a century. Non-linear effects expected to cause disruptions.</description></item><item><title>New Tech</title><link>/news/industry/new-tech/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:05:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/industry/new-tech/</guid><description>3D Printing and Advanced Materials Technology Carbon 3D Fast 3D printing of quality items in many possible shapes. Carbon3D partnerships means its printers are constructing Adidas footwear, NFL helmets, vehicle parts, and many other items
Food-as-software Coming soon&amp;hellip;
We are on the cusp of the deepest, fastest, most consequential disruption in food and agricultural production since the first domestication of plants and animals ten thousand years ago. This is primarily a protein disruption driven by economics.</description></item><item><title>Quotes, notable snippets</title><link>/media.quotes_and_poems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/media.quotes_and_poems/</guid><description>Fearful Thing to Love by Yehuda HaLevi (Judah HaLevi) Tis a Fearful Thing
‘Tis a fearful thing to love what death can touch.
A fearful thing to love, to hope, to dream, to be –
to be, And oh, to lose.
A thing for fools, this,
And a holy thing,
a holy thing to love.
For your life has lived in me, your laugh once lifted me, your word was gift to me.</description></item><item><title>Scientific Evidence of Worsening Effects of the Human Pollution Epidemic</title><link>/news/human-pollution-epidemic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 12:02:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/human-pollution-epidemic/</guid><description>Google it. In summary: don&amp;rsquo;t look and trust climate scientists.
The good news is climate change activism is working.
A Useful Framework for Dealing With This: If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in what kind of leadership it might take to guide all the peoples of the world out of this crisis, I invite you to look into Deep Adaptation. This is a professional and scientific term for the cultural and societal changes that will be needed to help the world transition maintain a more sustainable future without resorting to violence, pessimistic nihilism, paranoia of human extinction, or other fallacies similar ideologies may fall into.</description></item><item><title>DACA Timeline</title><link>/posts/daca-timeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 17:19:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/daca-timeline/</guid><description>A timelapse of the legal battles that tormented me in the past couple of years.</description></item><item><title>Code of Honor</title><link>/code_of_honor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 16:03:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>/code_of_honor/</guid><description>Silence is golden.</description></item><item><title>Programmer-for-hire</title><link>/swe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/swe/</guid><description>I may be available for software engineering contracting work.
With my full stack skillset, I can create (or update) a website, webapp, or Android app from start to finish.
Programming Languages I know the following languages:
Python including Tensorflow and other machine learning and data science tools. JavaScript including ES6, NodeJS, and other web development tools C C++, including Qt and the language QML Java Haskell Elm Lisp Rust I have experience with the Linux operating system.</description></item><item><title>Tutoring</title><link>/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutoring/</guid><description>I am your math, language, and programming tutor Qualifications: I worked as a tutor at the Computer Science department of the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology for two years. I have a degree in mathematics and a degree in computer science from the same school, where I graduated with a 3.5 GPA in 4.5 years. I tutored middle-school as part of the Growing Up Thinking Scientifically (GUTS) program and high-school students in the Supercomputing Challenge.</description></item><item><title>Internet Marketing</title><link>/internetmarketing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>/internetmarketing/</guid><description>Hi, I am your internet marketing guy Read more and contact me via emarketing.roguh.com Haga clic aquí para más información en publicista.roguh.com Skillset I have helped two small business in the USA build a compelling online presence. Contact me to talk about my portfolio and to get a free consultation. I can do the following:
Help you find an adequate domain name such as yourbusiness.com. Help you receive email at a professional looking address, such as ceo@yourbusiness.</description></item><item><title>Linux and MacOS configuration files</title><link>/confs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/confs/</guid><description>My portable, personal, developer-centric setup for common Linux and MacOS tools.</description></item><item><title>Some General Cybersecurity Advice</title><link>/tutorials/cybersec/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 04:04:16 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/cybersec/</guid><description>A mishmash of what could be common-sense security tips and other ideas for preventing security leaks on personal devices.</description></item><item><title>Security News</title><link>/news/industry/security-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 03:51:23 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/industry/security-news/</guid><description>Two of my cybersecurity courses at NMT asked students to write reports on recent security news. This continues to be a hobby of mine.
When Trump Phones Friends, the Chinese and the Russians Listen and Learn - A solar observatory in New Mexico is evacuated for a week and the FBI is in Inside the NSA&amp;#039;s War on Internet Security - SPIEGEL ONLINE How I Socially Engineer Myself Into High Security Facilities - Motherboard The Worst Cybersecurity Breaches of 2018 So Far | WIRED https://krebsonsecurity.</description></item><item><title>Contact Information</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description> hugo@roguh.com +1-505-465-9150 linkedin.com/in/hugoorivera/ Download my contact info (VCard .VCF format) keybase.io/roguh for encrypted communications. I&amp;rsquo;m also available on Signal and Telegram. linkedin.com/in/hugoorivera</description></item><item><title>Aliases + Names</title><link>/aliases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/aliases/</guid><description>My full name is Hugo Omar Rivera Calzadillas. I prefer the Spanish pronunciation oo-GOH.
I use Hugo O. Rivera for the sake of conciseness, memorability, and SEO.
Many institutions are unaware of or unwilling to accommodate the rich diversity of personal names around the world; therefore, I use:
Hugo Rivera Hugo Omar Rivera Hugo O. Rivera-Calzadillas Hugo Rivera-Calzadillas Hugo O. Rivera Calzadillas Hugo Rivera Calzadillas Screen names roguh (ro-KOO): Inspired by Rokurōta Makabe, a character in one of my favorite movies, The Hidden Fortress directed by Akira Kurosawa.</description></item><item><title>pympw</title><link>/projects/pympw/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 08:09:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/pympw/</guid><description>A Python implementation of the Master Password algorithm v3 with a nice Linux CLI</description></item><item><title>Best Websites</title><link>/websites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 02:19:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>/websites/</guid><description>In order, as determined by the knowledge graph and me:
https://github.com/resir014/thebestmotherfuckingwebsite.co https://motherfuckingwebsite.com/ https://thebestmotherfucking.website/ http://bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com/ https://evenbettermotherfucking.website/ https://perfectmotherfuckingwebsite.com/ https://thebestmotherfuckingwebsite.co/</description></item><item><title>polybar-themer</title><link>/projects/polybar-themer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 07:04:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/polybar-themer/</guid><description>A theme generator for polybar, a popular status bar for Linux. Uses math and advanced YAML parsing to generate colorful, sensible color schemes.</description></item><item><title>Parser and Interpreter in OCaml</title><link>/projects/hrclox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 20:21:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/hrclox/</guid><description>Lox interpreter written in OCaml by Hugo O. Rivera Calzadillas. See github.com/roguh/hrclox.
Based off https://craftinginterpreters.com.
Boilerplate code for writing parsers in OCaml using Menhir + sedlex See github.com/roguh/ocaml-parsing
(Unfinished, but the parser is fairly complete)</description></item><item><title>cuda-fft</title><link>/projects/cuda-fft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 22:53:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/cuda-fft/</guid><description>Yet another FFT implementation in CUDA. Includes benchmarks using simple data for comparing different implementations.</description></item><item><title>Pandoc wrappers</title><link>/projects/pandoc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 08:12:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/pandoc/</guid><description>Shortcuts and templates for writing résumés, math homework, and cheatsheets in Pandoc.</description></item><item><title>GameMaker mirrors</title><link>/mirrors/gamemaker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mirrors/gamemaker/</guid><description>GameMaker game decompilers</description></item><item><title>POC||GTFO mirrors</title><link>/mirrors/pocorgtfo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mirrors/pocorgtfo/</guid><description>Some reliable POC||GTFO mirrors</description></item><item><title>tetris-for-two</title><link>/projects/tetris-for-two/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 05:13:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/tetris-for-two/</guid><description>Tetris for two. A fun tetris game with many different game modes</description></item><item><title>PhotoFest</title><link>/projects/photofest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 02:06:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/photofest/</guid><description>PhotoFest is a secure self-hosted flat-file photo collection webapp written in Rust (unfinished)</description></item><item><title>Code for a statistics class</title><link>/projects/email-classifier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 01:17:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/email-classifier/</guid><description>Email classifier A machine learning project for classifying emails into spam and ham. Uses C for preprocessing emails, Python for parsing and extracting low-level features of emails, and a few lines of Matlab for running several classic classifiers.
See github.com/roguh/email-classifier
Hopfield testing These Python scripts can be used to test the recall effectiveness of Hopfield Networks. A sample dataset composed of the Walsh vectors, an orthogonal system is included by default.</description></item><item><title>Early Haskell Projects</title><link>/projects/earlyhaskell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/earlyhaskell/</guid><description>SCMinHS A Scheme Implementation in Haskell. Followed &amp;ldquo;Write Yourself a Scheme in 48 Hours. See github.com/roguh/SCMinHS.
coolnoise Parser and generator for programs written in the Classroom Object-Oriented Language. Eases testing of lexer and parser. See github.com/roguh/coolnoise.
An interpreter for the low-level CORE language Haskell was once compiled to a language called CORE.
See github.com/roguh/CORE</description></item><item><title>New Mexico Tech's Introduction to Python and Programming Labs (CS 107)</title><link>/tutorials/nmt_python_labs_cs107/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 22:53:34 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/nmt_python_labs_cs107/</guid><description>Carefully written and formatted. I wrote much of the copy-editing and some of the LaTeX for this year&amp;rsquo;s version of the labs.</description></item><item><title>cv-composer</title><link>/projects/cv-composer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 21:49:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/cv-composer/</guid><description>Command-line based computer vision algorithms showcase. Uses the OpenCV C++ library.</description></item><item><title>Notes on Chemistry the Central Science</title><link>/tutorials/chemistry_the_central_science/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 22:53:34 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/chemistry_the_central_science/</guid><description>See github.com/roguh/chemistry_the_central_science.</description></item><item><title>Notes on Perception for Design</title><link>/tutorials/perception_for_design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 22:53:34 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/perception_for_design/</guid><description>I took concise notes based on the excellent, scientifically-rigorous textbook Information Visualization: Perception for Design by Colin Ware. I created this PDF using LaTeX, which allowed me the flexibility to create an easy-to-edit, elegant, and compact document layout. I highly recommend the book and these notes for anyone that needs to create data visualizations.
See here.</description></item><item><title>Animated Periodic Table D3</title><link>/projects/animated-periodic-table-d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 18:25:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/animated-periodic-table-d3/</guid><description>A periodic table created in CoffeeScript and D3 with animated transitions.</description></item><item><title>The Great Silence</title><link>/stories/the_great_silence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/the_great_silence/</guid><description>The humans use Arecibo to look for extraterrestrial intelligence. Their desire to make a connection is so strong that they’ve created an ear capable of hearing across the universe.
But I and my fellow parrots are right here. Why aren’t they interested in listening to our voices?
We’re a non-human species capable of communicating with them. Aren’t we exactly what humans are looking for?
* The universe is so vast that intelligent life must surely have arisen many times.</description></item><item><title>Town of Cats</title><link>/stories/town_of_cats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/town_of_cats/</guid><description>At Koenji Station, Tengo boarded the Chuo Line inbound rapid-service train. The car was empty. He had nothing planned that day. Wherever he went and whatever he did (or didn’t do) was entirely up to him. It was ten o’clock on a windless summer morning, and the sun was beating down. The train passed Shinjuku, Yotsuya, Ochanomizu, and arrived at Tokyo Central Station, the end of the line. Everyone got off, and Tengo followed suit.</description></item><item><title>Exhalation</title><link>/stories/exhalation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/exhalation/</guid><description>It has long been said that air (which others call argon) is the source of life. This is not in fact the case, and I engrave these words to describe how I came to understand the true source of life and, as a corollary, the means by which life will one day end.
For most of history, the proposition that we drew life from air was so obvious that there was no need to assert it.</description></item><item><title>What's Expected of Us</title><link>/stories/what_is_expected_of_us/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/what_is_expected_of_us/</guid><description>This is a warning. Please read carefully.
By now you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen a Predictor; millions of them have been sold by the time you&amp;rsquo;re reading this. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t seen one, it&amp;rsquo;s a small device, like a remote for opening your car door. Its only features are a button and a big green LED. The light flashes if you press the button. Specifically, the light flashes one second before you press the button.</description></item><item><title>Darkrose and Diamond</title><link>/stories/darkrose_and_diamond/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/darkrose_and_diamond/</guid><description>Darkrose and Diamond A Boat Song from West Havnor Where my love is going There will I go. Where his boat is rowing I will row. We will laugh together, Together we will cry. If he lives I will live, If he dies I die. Where my love is going There will I go. Where his boat is rowing I will row.  IN THE WEST OF HAVNOR, among hills forested with oak and chestnut, is the town of Glade.</description></item><item><title>On Seeing the 100% Perfect Girl One Beautiful April Morning</title><link>/stories/on_seeing_the_one_hundred_percent_perfect_girl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/on_seeing_the_one_hundred_percent_perfect_girl/</guid><description>One beautiful April morning, on a narrow side street in Tokyo’s fashionable Harujuku neighborhood, I walked past the 100% perfect girl.
Tell you the truth, she’s not that good-looking. She doesn’t stand out in any way. Her clothes are nothing special. The back of her hair is still bent out of shape from sleep. She isn’t young, either - must be near thirty, not even close to a “girl,” properly speaking.</description></item><item><title>El Jardín de los Senderos que se Bifurcan</title><link>/stories/senderos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1941 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/senderos/</guid><description>A Victoria Ocampo
En la página 22 de la Historia de la Guerra Europea, de Liddell Hart, se lee que una ofensiva de trece divisiones británicas (apoyadas por mil cuatrocientas piezas de artillería) contra la línea Serre Montauban había sido planeada para el veinticuatro de julio de 1916 y debió postergarse hasta la mañana del día veintinueve. Las lluvias torrenciales (anota el capitán Liddell Hart) provocaron esa demora -nada significativa, por cierto-.</description></item><item><title>La Biblioteca de Babel</title><link>/stories/la_biblioteca_de_babel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1941 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/la_biblioteca_de_babel/</guid><description>El universo (que otros llaman la Biblioteca) se compone de un número indefinido, y tal vez infinito, de galerías hexagonales, con vastos pozos de ventilación en el medio, cercados por barandas bajísimas. Desde cualquier hexágono se ven los pisos inferiores y superiores: interminablemente. La distribución de las galerías es invariable. Veinte anaqueles, a cinco largos anaqueles por lado, cubren todos los lados menos dos; su altura, que es la de los pisos, excede apenas la de un bibliotecario normal.</description></item><item><title>The Library of Babel</title><link>/stories/the_library_of_babel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1941 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/the_library_of_babel/</guid><description>By this art you may contemplate the variations of the 23 letters&amp;hellip;
The Anatomy of Melancholy, part 2, sect. II, mem. IV
The universe (which others call the Library) is composed of an indefinite and perhaps infinite number of hexagonal galleries, with vast air shafts between, surrounded by very low railings. From any of the hexagons one can see, interminably, the upper and lower floors. The distribution of the galleries is invariable.</description></item><item><title>A brief autobiography</title><link>/bio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/bio/</guid><description>Early life I was born in Ciudad Cuauhtémoc in Chihuahua, México.
In my early teens, I made videogames using Dutch computer scientist Mark Overmaars' GameMaker Version 7.0.
I went to high school in Santa Fe, New Mexico. My teacher helped me get accepted into the CAMP (Complexity and Modeling Program) summer camp at Groton, Massachusetts, hosted by the Santa Fe Institute. We learned how to program agent-based simulations using NetLogo and the still new science of Complexity.</description></item><item><title>Business Card</title><link>/businesscard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/businesscard/</guid><description>Hugo O. Rivera roguh.com hugo@roguh.com github.com/roguh linkedin.com/in/roguh 505-819-7015</description></item><item><title>Career</title><link>/career/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/career/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about developing tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s essential technology. I work remotely as a software engineer in the high desert at sunny Santa Fe, NM.
Fullstack software engineer Working remotely from Santa Fe, NM (2020-) for PowerFlex (2019-) Electric vehicle charging stations and battery systems for buildings I work remotely building software to facilitate adaptive load management for large-scale electric-vehicle charging station deployments, and energy storage at PowerFlex, a recently acquired subsidiary of EDF Renewables, which is itself the North American branch of the renewable energy branch of an enormous multinational French energy company Électricité de France that powers much of the world using nuclear, solar, and wind energy.</description></item><item><title>Hugo O. Rivera's language cheatsheet</title><link>/about_language_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about_language_cheatsheet/</guid><description>Read about them here</description></item><item><title>Hugo O. Rivera's language cheatsheet</title><link>/language_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/language_cheatsheet/</guid><description>Read about them here</description></item><item><title>New Mexico</title><link>/nm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nm/</guid><description>The 47th state in the UNITED STATES OF AMERICA. Known for lowriders, U+1F47Ds, green chile, [beautiful wilderness](see 35.938,-106.204), and Meow Wolf&amp;rsquo;s House of Eternal Return.</description></item><item><title>USHANKA</title><link>/ushanka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ushanka/</guid><description>the angles cut me when i try to think it feels like thinking through cheese wire there&amp;rsquo;s no feeling but the no-feeling hurts it&amp;rsquo;s cold and it hurts the maze is sharp on my mind. the angles cut me when i try to think.</description></item></channel></rss>