<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>core lang on Hugo O. Rivera</title><link>/tags/core-lang/</link><description>Recent content in core lang on Hugo O. Rivera</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/core-lang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Programmer-for-hire</title><link>/swe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/swe/</guid><description>I may be available for software engineering contracting work.
With my full stack skillset, I can create (or update) a website, webapp, or Android app from start to finish.
Programming Languages I know the following languages:
Python including Tensorflow and other machine learning and data science tools. JavaScript including ES6, NodeJS, and other web development tools C C++, including Qt and the language QML Java Haskell Elm Lisp Rust I have experience with the Linux operating system.</description></item><item><title>Tutoring</title><link>/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutoring/</guid><description>I am your math, language, and programming tutor Qualifications: I worked as a tutor at the Computer Science department of the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology for two years. I have a degree in mathematics and a degree in computer science from the same school, where I graduated with a 3.5 GPA in 4.5 years. I tutored middle-school as part of the Growing Up Thinking Scientifically (GUTS) program and high-school students in the Supercomputing Challenge.</description></item><item><title>Early Haskell Projects</title><link>/projects/earlyhaskell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/earlyhaskell/</guid><description>SCMinHS A Scheme Implementation in Haskell. Followed &amp;ldquo;Write Yourself a Scheme in 48 Hours. See github.com/roguh/SCMinHS.
coolnoise Parser and generator for programs written in the Classroom Object-Oriented Language. Eases testing of lexer and parser. See github.com/roguh/coolnoise.
An interpreter for the low-level CORE language Haskell was once compiled to a language called CORE.
See github.com/roguh/CORE</description></item></channel></rss>