<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sysadmin on Hugo O. Rivera's website</title><link>https://roguh.com/tags/sysadmin/</link><description>Recent content in sysadmin on Hugo O. Rivera's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roguh.com/tags/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Programmer-for-hire</title><link>https://roguh.com/swe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/swe/</guid><description>I may be available for software engineering contracting work.
With my full stack skillset, I can create (or update) a website, webapp, or Android app from start to finish.
Programming Languages I know the following languages:
Python including Tensorflow and other machine learning and data science tools. JavaScript including ES6, NodeJS, and other web development tools C C++, including Qt and the language QML Java Haskell Elm Lisp Rust I have experience with the Linux operating system.</description></item><item><title>Tutoring</title><link>https://roguh.com/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/tutoring/</guid><description>I am your math, language, and programming tutor Qualifications: I worked as a tutor at the Computer Science department of the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology for two years. I have a degree in mathematics and a degree in computer science from the same school, where I graduated with a 3.5 GPA in 4.5 years. I tutored middle-school as part of the Growing Up Thinking Scientifically (GUTS) program and high-school students in the Supercomputing Challenge.</description></item><item><title>Linux and MacOS configuration files</title><link>https://roguh.com/confs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/confs/</guid><description>My portable, personal, developer-centric setup for common Linux and MacOS tools.</description></item><item><title>Some General Cybersecurity Advice</title><link>https://roguh.com/tutorials/cybersec/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 04:04:16 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/tutorials/cybersec/</guid><description>A mishmash of what could be common-sense security tips and other ideas for preventing security leaks on personal devices.</description></item><item><title>Security News</title><link>https://roguh.com/news/industry/security-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 03:51:23 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/news/industry/security-news/</guid><description>Two of my cybersecurity courses at NMT asked students to write reports on recent security news. This continues to be a hobby of mine.
When Trump Phones Friends, the Chinese and the Russians Listen and Learn - A solar observatory in New Mexico is evacuated for a week and the FBI is in Inside the NSA&amp;#039;s War on Internet Security - SPIEGEL ONLINE How I Socially Engineer Myself Into High Security Facilities - Motherboard The Worst Cybersecurity Breaches of 2018 So Far | WIRED https://krebsonsecurity.</description></item></channel></rss>