<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shell on Hugo O. Rivera</title><link>/tags/shell/</link><description>Recent content in Shell on Hugo O. Rivera</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 19:47:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shellscripts: gp and parallely</title><link>/projects/shellscripts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 19:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/shellscripts/</guid><description>Some functions for computing using the Long Count, a Mayan numeric system for dates.</description></item><item><title>Programmer-for-hire</title><link>/swe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/swe/</guid><description>I may be available for software engineering contracting work.
With my full stack skillset, I can create (or update) a website, webapp, or Android app from start to finish.
Programming Languages I know the following languages:
Python including Tensorflow and other machine learning and data science tools. JavaScript including ES6, NodeJS, and other web development tools C C++, including Qt and the language QML Java Haskell Elm Lisp Rust I have experience with the Linux operating system.</description></item><item><title>Tutoring</title><link>/tutoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 19:10:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>/tutoring/</guid><description>I am your math, language, and programming tutor Qualifications: I worked as a tutor at the Computer Science department of the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology for two years. I have a degree in mathematics and a degree in computer science from the same school, where I graduated with a 3.5 GPA in 4.5 years. I tutored middle-school as part of the Growing Up Thinking Scientifically (GUTS) program and high-school students in the Supercomputing Challenge.</description></item><item><title>Linux and MacOS configuration files</title><link>/confs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>/confs/</guid><description>My portable, personal, developer-centric setup for common Linux and MacOS tools.</description></item><item><title>polybar-themer</title><link>/projects/polybar-themer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 07:04:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/polybar-themer/</guid><description>A theme generator for polybar, a popular status bar for Linux. Uses math and advanced YAML parsing to generate colorful, sensible color schemes.</description></item><item><title>cuda-fft</title><link>/projects/cuda-fft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 22:53:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/cuda-fft/</guid><description>Yet another FFT implementation in CUDA. Includes benchmarks using simple data for comparing different implementations.</description></item><item><title>Pandoc wrappers</title><link>/projects/pandoc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 08:12:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/pandoc/</guid><description>Shortcuts and templates for writing résumés, math homework, and cheatsheets in Pandoc.</description></item><item><title>tetris-for-two</title><link>/projects/tetris-for-two/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 05:13:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/tetris-for-two/</guid><description>Tetris for two. A fun tetris game with many different game modes</description></item><item><title>Code for a statistics class</title><link>/projects/email-classifier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 01:17:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/email-classifier/</guid><description>Email classifier A machine learning project for classifying emails into spam and ham. Uses C for preprocessing emails, Python for parsing and extracting low-level features of emails, and a few lines of Matlab for running several classic classifiers.
See github.com/roguh/email-classifier
Hopfield testing These Python scripts can be used to test the recall effectiveness of Hopfield Networks. A sample dataset composed of the Walsh vectors, an orthogonal system is included by default.</description></item><item><title>Early Haskell Projects</title><link>/projects/earlyhaskell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 15:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/earlyhaskell/</guid><description>SCMinHS A Scheme Implementation in Haskell. Followed &amp;ldquo;Write Yourself a Scheme in 48 Hours. See github.com/roguh/SCMinHS.
coolnoise Parser and generator for programs written in the Classroom Object-Oriented Language. Eases testing of lexer and parser. See github.com/roguh/coolnoise.
An interpreter for the low-level CORE language Haskell was once compiled to a language called CORE.
See github.com/roguh/CORE</description></item></channel></rss>