<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on Hugo O. Rivera's website</title><link>https://roguh.com/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on Hugo O. Rivera's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 12:47:07 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roguh.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contact Information</title><link>https://roguh.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/contact/</guid><description> hugo@roguh.com +1-505-465-9150 linkedin.com/in/hugoorivera/ Download my contact info (VCard .VCF format) keybase.io/roguh for encrypted communications. I&amp;rsquo;m also available on Signal and Telegram. linkedin.com/in/hugoorivera</description></item><item><title>Aliases + Names</title><link>https://roguh.com/aliases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:47:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/aliases/</guid><description>My full name is Hugo Omar Rivera Calzadillas. I prefer the Spanish pronunciation oo-GOH.
I use Hugo O. Rivera for the sake of conciseness, memorability, and SEO.
Many institutions are unaware of or unwilling to accommodate the rich diversity of personal names around the world; therefore, I use:
Hugo Rivera Hugo Omar Rivera Hugo O. Rivera-Calzadillas Hugo Rivera-Calzadillas Hugo O. Rivera Calzadillas Hugo Rivera Calzadillas Screen names roguh (ro-KOO): Inspired by Rokurōta Makabe, a character in one of my favorite movies, The Hidden Fortress directed by Akira Kurosawa.</description></item><item><title>A brief autobiography</title><link>https://roguh.com/bio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/bio/</guid><description>Early life I was born in Ciudad Cuauhtémoc in Chihuahua, México.
In my early teens, I made videogames using Dutch computer scientist Mark Overmaars' GameMaker Version 7.0.
I went to high school in Santa Fe, New Mexico. My teacher helped me get accepted into the CAMP (Complexity and Modeling Program) summer camp at Groton, Massachusetts, hosted by the Santa Fe Institute. We learned how to program agent-based simulations using NetLogo and the still new science of Complexity.</description></item><item><title>Career</title><link>https://roguh.com/career/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/career/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about developing tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s essential technology. I work remotely as a software engineer in the high desert at sunny Santa Fe, NM.
Fullstack software engineer Working remotely from Santa Fe, NM (2020-) for PowerFlex (2019-) Electric vehicle charging stations and battery systems for buildings I work remotely building software to facilitate adaptive load management for large-scale electric-vehicle charging station deployments, and energy storage at PowerFlex, a recently acquired subsidiary of EDF Renewables, which is itself the North American branch of the renewable energy branch of an enormous multinational French energy company Électricité de France that powers much of the world using nuclear, solar, and wind energy.</description></item><item><title>Hugo O. Rivera's language cheatsheet</title><link>https://roguh.com/about_language_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/about_language_cheatsheet/</guid><description>Read about them here</description></item><item><title>Hugo O. Rivera's language cheatsheet</title><link>https://roguh.com/language_cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roguh.com/language_cheatsheet/</guid><description>Read about them here</description></item></channel></rss>