<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on roguh's website</title><link>/categories/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on roguh's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:05:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Science</title><link>/news/industry/new-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:05:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/industry/new-science/</guid><description>Complexity Accept chaos.
Machine Learning Applied mathematics with the power of modern supercomputers. Advanced optimization, linear algebra, calculus.
Effectiveness of techniques revolutionized by deep learning.
Climate Change Consequences of pollution known for about a century. Non-linear effects expected to cause disruptions.</description></item><item><title>New Tech</title><link>/news/industry/new-tech/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 10:05:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/industry/new-tech/</guid><description>3D Printing and Advanced Materials Technology Carbon 3D Fast 3D printing of quality items in many possible shapes. Carbon3D partnerships means its printers are constructing Adidas footwear, NFL helmets, vehicle parts, and many other items
Food-as-software Coming soon&amp;hellip;
We are on the cusp of the deepest, fastest, most consequential disruption in food and agricultural production since the first domestication of plants and animals ten thousand years ago. This is primarily a protein disruption driven by economics.</description></item><item><title>Scientific Evidence of Worsening Effects of the Human Pollution Epidemic</title><link>/news/human-pollution-epidemic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 12:02:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/human-pollution-epidemic/</guid><description>Google it. In summary: don&amp;rsquo;t look and trust climate scientists.
The good news is climate change activism is working.
A Useful Framework for Dealing With This: If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in what kind of leadership it might take to guide all the peoples of the world out of this crisis, I invite you to look into Deep Adaptation. This is a professional and scientific term for the cultural and societal changes that will be needed to help the world transition maintain a more sustainable future without resorting to violence, pessimistic nihilism, paranoia of human extinction, or other fallacies similar ideologies may fall into.</description></item><item><title>Security News</title><link>/news/industry/security-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 03:51:23 -0700</pubDate><guid>/news/industry/security-news/</guid><description>Two of my cybersecurity courses at NMT asked students to write reports on recent security news. This continues to be a hobby of mine.
When Trump Phones Friends, the Chinese and the Russians Listen and Learn - A solar observatory in New Mexico is evacuated for a week and the FBI is in Inside the NSA&amp;#039;s War on Internet Security - SPIEGEL ONLINE How I Socially Engineer Myself Into High Security Facilities - Motherboard The Worst Cybersecurity Breaches of 2018 So Far | WIRED https://krebsonsecurity.</description></item></channel></rss>