<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stories on roguh's website</title><link>/stories/</link><description>Recent content in Stories on roguh's website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Great Silence</title><link>/stories/the_great_silence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/the_great_silence/</guid><description>The humans use Arecibo to look for extraterrestrial intelligence. Their desire to make a connection is so strong that they’ve created an ear capable of hearing across the universe.
But I and my fellow parrots are right here. Why aren’t they interested in listening to our voices?
We’re a non-human species capable of communicating with them. Aren’t we exactly what humans are looking for?
* The universe is so vast that intelligent life must surely have arisen many times.</description></item><item><title>Town of Cats</title><link>/stories/town_of_cats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/town_of_cats/</guid><description>At Koenji Station, Tengo boarded the Chuo Line inbound rapid-service train. The car was empty. He had nothing planned that day. Wherever he went and whatever he did (or didn’t do) was entirely up to him. It was ten o’clock on a windless summer morning, and the sun was beating down. The train passed Shinjuku, Yotsuya, Ochanomizu, and arrived at Tokyo Central Station, the end of the line. Everyone got off, and Tengo followed suit.</description></item><item><title>Exhalation</title><link>/stories/exhalation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/exhalation/</guid><description>It has long been said that air (which others call argon) is the source of life. This is not in fact the case, and I engrave these words to describe how I came to understand the true source of life and, as a corollary, the means by which life will one day end.
For most of history, the proposition that we drew life from air was so obvious that there was no need to assert it.</description></item><item><title>What's Expected of Us</title><link>/stories/what_is_expected_of_us/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/what_is_expected_of_us/</guid><description>This is a warning. Please read carefully.
By now you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen a Predictor; millions of them have been sold by the time you&amp;rsquo;re reading this. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t seen one, it&amp;rsquo;s a small device, like a remote for opening your car door. Its only features are a button and a big green LED. The light flashes if you press the button. Specifically, the light flashes one second before you press the button.</description></item><item><title>Darkrose and Diamond</title><link>/stories/darkrose_and_diamond/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/darkrose_and_diamond/</guid><description>Darkrose and Diamond A Boat Song from West Havnor Where my love is going There will I go. Where his boat is rowing I will row. We will laugh together, Together we will cry. If he lives I will live, If he dies I die. Where my love is going There will I go. Where his boat is rowing I will row. IN THE WEST OF HAVNOR, among hills forested with oak and chestnut, is the town of Glade.</description></item><item><title>On Seeing the 100% Perfect Girl One Beautiful April Morning</title><link>/stories/on_seeing_the_one_hundred_percent_perfect_girl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/on_seeing_the_one_hundred_percent_perfect_girl/</guid><description>One beautiful April morning, on a narrow side street in Tokyo’s fashionable Harujuku neighborhood, I walked past the 100% perfect girl.
Tell you the truth, she’s not that good-looking. She doesn’t stand out in any way. Her clothes are nothing special. The back of her hair is still bent out of shape from sleep. She isn’t young, either - must be near thirty, not even close to a “girl,” properly speaking.</description></item><item><title>El Jardín de los Senderos que se Bifurcan</title><link>/stories/senderos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1941 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/senderos/</guid><description>A Victoria Ocampo
En la página 22 de la Historia de la Guerra Europea, de Liddell Hart, se lee que una ofensiva de trece divisiones británicas (apoyadas por mil cuatrocientas piezas de artillería) contra la línea Serre Montauban había sido planeada para el veinticuatro de julio de 1916 y debió postergarse hasta la mañana del día veintinueve. Las lluvias torrenciales (anota el capitán Liddell Hart) provocaron esa demora -nada significativa, por cierto-.</description></item><item><title>La Biblioteca de Babel</title><link>/stories/la_biblioteca_de_babel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1941 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/la_biblioteca_de_babel/</guid><description>El universo (que otros llaman la Biblioteca) se compone de un número indefinido, y tal vez infinito, de galerías hexagonales, con vastos pozos de ventilación en el medio, cercados por barandas bajísimas. Desde cualquier hexágono se ven los pisos inferiores y superiores: interminablemente. La distribución de las galerías es invariable. Veinte anaqueles, a cinco largos anaqueles por lado, cubren todos los lados menos dos; su altura, que es la de los pisos, excede apenas la de un bibliotecario normal.</description></item><item><title>The Library of Babel</title><link>/stories/the_library_of_babel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1941 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/stories/the_library_of_babel/</guid><description>By this art you may contemplate the variations of the 23 letters&amp;hellip;
The Anatomy of Melancholy, part 2, sect. II, mem. IV
The universe (which others call the Library) is composed of an indefinite and perhaps infinite number of hexagonal galleries, with vast air shafts between, surrounded by very low railings. From any of the hexagons one can see, interminably, the upper and lower floors. The distribution of the galleries is invariable.</description></item></channel></rss>